Nightmares in Red, White and Blue is a documentary,
horror film directed by Andrew Monument.
An exploration of the appeal of horror films, with
interviews of many legendary directors in the genre.
Narrator (voice), played by Lance Henriksen.
Self, played by Larry Cohen.
Self, played by Joe Dante.
Self, played by John Carpenter.
Self, played by Darren Lynn Bousman.
Self, played by Mick Garris.
Nightmares in Red, White and Blue: The Evolution of the American Horror Film is a 2009 American documentary
film directed by Andrew Monument, based on the 2004 book of the same name by Joseph Maddrey.
The film examines the appeal of the horror film genre to audiences and how the genre has continually evolved
to reflect changing societal fears in the United States during the 20th and 21st centuries.
Nightmares in Red, White and Blue features interviews with such subjects as Larry Cohen, Joe
Dante, John Carpenter, Darren Lynn Bousman, Mick Garris, Tom McLoughlin, and George A.
Romero, and is narrated by Lance Henriksen.
It has received generally positive reviews.
The film explores themes of movie business,
interview, filmmaking, horror filmmaking.
The tone is dark.